<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ethan Peterson&#39;s Site</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ethan Peterson&#39;s Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A deeper look at MLB trends</title>
      <link>/2021/10/25/a-deeper-look-at-mlb-trends/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/10/25/a-deeper-look-at-mlb-trends/</guid>
      <description>Baseball is full of crazy trends. Some are incredibly impressive, like the New York Yankees winning five World Series championships (including four in a row) in the 1930s and six in the 1950s. Some are incredibly abysmal, like the Chicago Cubs’ 108-year drought without a World Series championship from 1908 to 2016.
In this blog, I’m going to be taking a look at four different types of trends in Major League Baseball and creating data visualizations for us to view using R-Studio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking at the worst games in 2019 football season</title>
      <link>/2021/10/25/looking-at-the-worst-games-in-2019-football-season/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/10/25/looking-at-the-worst-games-in-2019-football-season/</guid>
      <description>I am going to be going in depth and looking at the worst games in college football from the 2019 season.
First I need to load the correct library, tidyverse, and then load my data in, all of the games from the 2019 college football season.
library(tidyverse) ## ── Attaching packages ─────────────────────────────────────── tidyverse 1.3.1 ── ## ✓ ggplot2 3.3.5 ✓ purrr 0.3.4 ## ✓ tibble 3.1.5 ✓ dplyr 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Myself</title>
      <link>/2021/10/08/introducing-myself/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/10/08/introducing-myself/</guid>
      <description>My name is Ethan Peterson. I was born and raised in small-town Nebraska. I graduated from Cross County High School in Stromsburg, NE. I am currently attending the University of Nebraska-Lincoln majoring in sociology and minoring in statistics.
I’ve always had a giant passion for sports. Baseball was, and still is, my favorite sport. I grew up a die hard Yankees fan (thanks to my father, who, has no relation to the state of New York.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>21-year old sports fanatic who has a passion for visualizing trends and data for myself and friends. Huge New York Yankees, Nebraska Cornhuskers, Los Angeles Lakers, and Cleveland Browns fan (in that order).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
