<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>basketball on Ethan Peterson&#39;s Site</title>
    <link>/tags/basketball/</link>
    <description>Recent content in basketball on Ethan Peterson&#39;s Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/basketball/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Predicting NBA Games with a Model Proves Challenging </title>
      <link>/2022/04/25/predicting-nba-games-with-a-model-proves-challenging/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2022/04/25/predicting-nba-games-with-a-model-proves-challenging/</guid>
      <description>Explaining methods, features of the model, and algorithm here.
–
When it came to deciding whether or not we wanted to go with the model’s choice of who would win or not for our bets, we tended to rely more on who we felt would win the games over the model’s choice instead. The model doesn’t know who is playing, momentum, and other obscene and abstract factors that we can’t sum up and put into a model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search for the Best Worst NBA Team of All Time</title>
      <link>/2022/02/10/search-for-the-best-worst-nba-team-of-all-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2022/02/10/search-for-the-best-worst-nba-team-of-all-time/</guid>
      <description>Unfinished, work in progress
Every year, the NBA ends its regular season with three different types of teams. The best overall team, the middle team(s), and the worst overall team. This has been a constant in the sport’s 75-year history. You either have the best record, the worst record, or somewhere in between. The team with the best record (and 19 of the middle teams, now, thanks to the play-in tournament) get a chance to move on and compete in the playoffs, while the team with the worst record and nine similar-record teams pack up and head home early and prepare for the next season.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decadal GOATs of the NBA</title>
      <link>/2021/12/06/decadal-goats-of-the-nba/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/12/06/decadal-goats-of-the-nba/</guid>
      <description>&#34;The First true basketball game as we know it was on January 20th, 1892 in Springfield, Massachusetts. Canadian Doctor James Naismith invented the game for the YMCA to play during the winter months. Naismith wrote simple rules for the game, and nailed up two peach baskets for hoops, most of original Naismith rules are still in place today. Some of the rules have changed a bit, and new rules have been added since then, such as in the original game bouncing the ball was prohibited.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
