<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Ethan Peterson&#39;s Site</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Ethan Peterson&#39;s Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Predicting March Madness with a Model is Hard</title>
      <link>/2022/03/26/predicting-march-madness-with-a-model-is-hard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2022/03/26/predicting-march-madness-with-a-model-is-hard/</guid>
      <description>This spring, our SPMC 460 class was tasked with creating a machine learning model to predict the outcome of the Men’s March Madness tournament. We had multiple options of models to choose from: logistic regression, random forest, XGBoost, and support vector machines. I elected to go with a support vector machine (SVM), simply because it seemed like it would work the best for me.
## Setting default kernel parameters ## line search fails -1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search for the Best Worst NBA Team of All Time</title>
      <link>/2022/02/10/search-for-the-best-worst-nba-team-of-all-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2022/02/10/search-for-the-best-worst-nba-team-of-all-time/</guid>
      <description>Every year, the NBA ends its regular season with three different types of teams. The best overall team, the middle team(s), and the worst overall team. This has been a constant in the sport’s 75-year history. You either have the best record, the worst record, or somewhere in between. The team with the best record (and 19 of the middle teams, now, thanks to the play-in tournament) get a chance to move on and compete in the playoffs, while the team with the worst record and nine similar-record teams pack up and head home early and prepare for the next season.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decadal GOATs of the NBA</title>
      <link>/2021/12/06/decadal-goats-of-the-nba/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/12/06/decadal-goats-of-the-nba/</guid>
      <description>&#34;The First true basketball game as we know it was on January 20th, 1892 in Springfield, Massachusetts. Canadian Doctor James Naismith invented the game for the YMCA to play during the winter months. Naismith wrote simple rules for the game, and nailed up two peach baskets for hoops, most of original Naismith rules are still in place today. Some of the rules have changed a bit, and new rules have been added since then, such as in the original game bouncing the ball was prohibited.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three NBA trends to follow</title>
      <link>/2021/12/05/three-nba-trends-to-follow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/12/05/three-nba-trends-to-follow/</guid>
      <description>The NBA is in the midst of a game style shift. The 3-point shot is being attempted at record high numbers, and virtually every other shot at record lows. I’m interested to see how 3-point attempts (3PA) have changed in recent years and if there’s been an effect on rookies becoming more long-ball focused. As an unrelated bonus, I’m going to look at Dean Oliver’s “Four Factors of Basketball Success” when compared to championship teams.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A deeper look at MLB trends</title>
      <link>/2021/10/25/a-deeper-look-at-mlb-trends/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/10/25/a-deeper-look-at-mlb-trends/</guid>
      <description>Baseball is full of crazy trends. Some are incredibly impressive, like the New York Yankees winning five World Series championships (including four in a row) in the 1930s and six in the 1950s. Some are incredibly abysmal, like the Chicago Cubs’ 108-year drought without a World Series championship from 1908 to 2016.
In this blog, I’m going to be taking a look at four different types of trends in Major League Baseball and creating data visualizations for us to view using R-Studio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking at the worst games in 2019 football season</title>
      <link>/2021/10/25/looking-at-the-worst-games-in-2019-football-season/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/10/25/looking-at-the-worst-games-in-2019-football-season/</guid>
      <description>I am going to be going in depth and looking at the worst games in college football from the 2019 season.
First I need to load the correct library, tidyverse, and then load my data in, all of the games from the 2019 college football season.
library(tidyverse) badlogs &amp;lt;- read_csv(&amp;quot;~/Desktop/SPMC 350 Files/homework/data/badfootballlogs19.csv&amp;quot;) First, I need to fix the Result column. Currently, its data is in W/L format and I want separate columns called Outcome and Score using the separate command.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Myself</title>
      <link>/2021/10/08/introducing-myself/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/10/08/introducing-myself/</guid>
      <description>My name is Ethan Peterson. I was born and raised in small-town Nebraska. I graduated from Cross County High School in Stromsburg, NE. I am currently attending the University of Nebraska-Lincoln majoring in sociology and minoring in statistics.
I’ve always had a giant passion for sports. Baseball was, and still is, my favorite sport. I grew up a die hard Yankees fan (thanks to my father, who, has no relation to the state of New York.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
